CORRIGAN BAKER

Simcoe, ON
Portfolio - Github - Trailhead - LinkedIn
corriganbaker@gmail.com

A creative and passionate professional with experience in web development, graphic design, and music education. A strong interest in working with AI and machine learning. Known to have a strong work ethic and talent in applying analytical and creative thinking to develop user-friendly interfaces.

EXPERIENCE

100Devs, January 2022 – Present

Full-Stack Developer

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices.
- Built modern UI using CSS grid, flexbox, JavaScript and Figma.
- Applied agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management.

CorriCodes, November 2021 – Present

Web Development & Design

- Created responsive websites for online music school and portfolio using HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- SQL & NoSQL database administration, as well as embedding security tokens such as CSRF.
- Built various games and applications such as the Google T-Rex run game, weather app & and online store with authentication and security features.
- Set up meetings with clients on RemoteHQ to plan and design their website prototypes or mood boards using the built-in Figma application and Miro Board.

Merriam School Of Music, June 2011 – Present

Music Education Specialist

Formerly Administrative Assistant & Bookstore Associate

- Educated students of all ages, levels and learning styles through online learning using LearnCube, Google Meet, Discord & RemoteHQ.
- Organized lesson plans, recitals and exam preparation with the use of Miro Boards, Google Drive
 Classroom applications.
- Troubleshot with IT, quickly looked for a backup solution to technical issues in online lessons and researched different video platforms that could be used for teaching.
- Designed posters, brochures, lesson plans, slideshows and worksheets for students' lessons, recitals, exams and promotions using Canva or Photoshop.
- Increased customer retention with creative teaching methods, assisted in scheduling lessons and set up payment plans with Salesforce Administration.
- Tracked inventory, processed orders from the online bookstore, booked piano tunings, and metric tracking.

Green Party Of Canada, September 2021 – Present

- Promoted platform on social media and in the Norfolk & Haldimand County areas.
- Informed and educated on low-waste solutions, Guaranteed Living Income action plan, saving Canada's old growth forests, and the transition of oil and coal workers into a greener industry.

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Languages: Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python, Git.
- Frameworks & Libraries: React, Vue, Angular, Tailwind, Bootstrap 5, WordPress, Node, jQuery, Github, StackOverflow, Unsplash, Unicons.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Salesforce.
- Software: Photoshop, Excel, Figma, Spline, Miro, Canva, Protools, Microsoft Office & Google.
- Methodologies: OOP, SCRUM, Agile.

Language Skills

- Basic French, German & Italian.
- Highly proficient in transcription using the International Phonetic Alphabet.

EDUCATION

BA in Applied Music, 2011-2015

Jazz Voice & Music Technology Mohawk College | Hamilton, ON

General Arts & Science College Certificate, 2007-2008

University Profile
Sheridan College | Oakville, ON

CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp
June 2022

100 Days Of Code

Academind April 2022

Introduction To Coding

SheCodes
November 2021

Level 8 Voice Certificate

Royal Conservatory of Canada August 2020

Level 6 Piano Certificate

Royal Conservatory of Canada June 2015